Okay, so the rest of this is the validation code so we can,
最后是验证代码
kind of, keep track of the performance of our word2vec network as it's training.
这些代码可以让我们跟踪 word2vec 网络的训练表现
And then here is some training code.
这是训练代码
This is, you know,
这
fairly, fairly typical way of doing it.
是种十分典型的实现方法
So you just create your batches and then create
就是创建批次
a feed dictionary and pass it into your network and run the optimizer.
然后创建字典 feed 将字典传递给网络 然后运行优化器
So then here as it's training,
这里可以看到 训练时
we'll be printing out
我们会输出训练损失
the training loss so you should be seeing this drop as it's going on.
这样你就可以看到训练过程的舍弃情况了
And then we're also printing out some words for validation.
我们还要输出一些单词来进行验证
So what we did here is just kind of randomly sample some target words,
所以在这里 我们随机抽样出一些目标单词
some kind of like example words and then we're looking at, you know,
一些示例单词 然后观察
words in our dataset where the vector representations are close.
数据集里那些向量表征相似的单词
Right? So this, we can see like, oh, is our,
是不是这个理？ 这样我们就能知道 哦
is our network actually learning,
网络真的在学习
you know, semantic relationships between these words?
单词间的语义联系
So as it is learning you should start
在网络学习时 打个比方
seeing like words that are related to called being close to called.
你应该会看到与 called 关联的单词 也就是接近它的单词
So this is showing like, okay,
比如
nearest to the word for is Hoffman, rogue, Montinari.
最靠近 for (为了) 的单词是 Hoffman (霍夫曼)、rogue (流氓) 和 Montinari (蒙蒂纳里)
I mean these words obviously do not have
显然 这些单词
anything to do with any of this stuff or like consists,
风马牛不相及
you know, scale, like it doesn't really have anything to do with this.
像是 consists (组成) 或 scale (规模) 真的和这些没什么关系
But at the end like when we, when we have this all trained up,
但到了最后 网络训练好了
we can see, you know, like the word scale,
我们就会看到 比如单词 scale
the, the word diatonic is close to scale and this is, you know,
单词 diatonic (自然音阶的) 与 scale 很接近
a musical phrase or we have units and unit, ice rink,
因为两者是常见的英语音乐短语 类似的还有 units  和 unit
USSR, hockey, Sweden, you know,
ice (冰) 和 rink (溜冰)、USSR (苏联)、hockey (曲棍球)、sweden (瑞典)
like a lot of this has to do with,
这些单词之间
you know, hockey, like ice rink, hockey.
hockey 和 ice、rink 之间都有关系
So we can, we can use this to actually get a sense of how our,
通过这个变化
our network is learning and how these representations are actually,
我们可以感觉到网络的确在学习 知道这些表征在
you know, getting closer to each other in a way that we want.
逐渐以我们想要的方式接近彼此
Okay, so then finally here I am using T-SNE to, kind of,
好了 最后在这里我用 T-SNE
group our vectors together so we can get a visualization
来把向量归类分组
of like how these representations actually exist in this,
将这些表征
sort of, you know, high dimensional space.
在高维空间中可视化出来
So what we expect to see is that words that have similar meanings are
我们预计有相似意义的单词
going to be closer together and that's basically exactly what we see.
会靠近彼此 而这基本上符合我们的预期
So here we have like Central,
比如这里 central (中央的)、
East, Western, West, South, North America.
east (东)、 western (西方的)、west (西)、south (南)、North America (北美洲)
So, you know, these all like exist in the same, same context,
因为这些位于同一语境
and so then we see them grouped together with our, our semantic representations.
所以语义表征将其归类到一起
Then over here you have school, university, college.
这边则有 school (学校)、university (大学)、college (学院)
Down here we have like open source, free, software.
这下面则是 open source (开源)、free (自由)、software (软件)
So you know, like all these things,
像这些单词
so it's a pretty good indication that our network has actually
很好地体现了网络
learned like some information about like the meaning of these words.
真的学到了一些信息 比如词义
Okay, I hope you enjoyed building this.
好了 希望你喜欢这个网络的建立过程
This is a really cool like architecture,
这真的是个很酷的结构
a really cool model that has proven to
一个很酷的模型 而且事实证明
be really useful in representing language. Okay, cheers. 最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6
这个模型很适合进行语言表征 好了 希望你学得愉快